Democratic Study Group Records
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Subject File, 1912-1995 (Box II:102-185)
  - Rules (Box II:159)
    - Project Saltmine, index-digest of House precedents
      - Research file
        - Privilege of bills and resolutions, 1932-1955
        - Privilege of the House of Representatives, 1932-1965, undated, (1 folder) (Box II:161)
        - Quorum call, 1932, 1942, 1950, 1958
        - Ramsmeyer rule, 1932-1966
        - Recognition, 1950-1952, 1963, undated
        - Recommittal, 1912, 1932-1965
        - Reference of bills to committee, 1934-1939
        - Rules changes, 1965
        - Rules of the House of Representatives, 1949-1965
        - Time for raising point of order, 1938-1956, 1966
        - Untitled, 1931-1966
        - Voting qualification, 1937-1948, 1957, 1965
        - Words taken down and decorum, 1934-1964
    - Proposed changes, 1984-1988, undated, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:162)
    - Special orders and one-minute speeches, 1984-1985, undated
    - Task force on rules changes, 1983-1984
  - Secrecy, 1970-1973, 1979, (2 folders)
  - Select Committee on Ethics, 1977
  - Select Committee on Committees (Bolling Committee) See Container II:131, same heading
  - Sellers, Gary, 1972, undated
  - Selma-Montgomery civil rights march, 1965
    - Affidavits
    - Dickinson, William L.
    - Huntley-Brinkley report
    - Miscellany, 1965-1966
    - News clippings (Box II:163)
  - Seniority
    - Chronological file, 1956, 1964-1975, undated, (3 folders)
    - Correspondence, 1970
    - Hansen Committee See Container II:127, Committee on Organization, Study, and Review, 1970-1971
    - News clippings, 1961-1970
    - Printed matter, 1935, 1956-1975, undated, (3 folders)
    - Resolutions, 1970
    - Study, circa 1973
    - Sobell, Morton, 1953-1965 (Box II:164)
  - Social security
    - Chronological file, 1964, 1972, 1981-1985
    - Jepsen, Roger W., 1977-1982
    - Votes, 1969, 1980-1982
  - Spingarn, Stephen J., 1956, 1963-1966
  - Sullivan, Lawrence, coordinator of information, House of Representatives, 1948, 1955, 1961-1966
  - Survey research
    - Congressional reform
      - 1976
      - 1978
        - Correspondence
        - Responses
          - General, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:165)
          - Supplemental question
        - Tabulation and analysis
      - 1980
        - Responses, (3 folders)
        - Tabulation
    - New rule on advance notice of amendments, 1977, (2 folders) (Box II:166)
    - Revenue options, 1987
    - Rules change, 1980-1982, (2 folders)
    - Rules changes and congressional pay, 1982
      - Responses, (2 folders)
      - Tabulation
  - Tax reform
    - Budget and deficit reduction, 1983, (2 folders)
    - “Capital gains tax proposal,” 1978 (Box II:167)
    - Chronological file
      - 1969-1990, (4 folders)
      - 1993
    - “DSG Fact Book,” 1969
    - Economic Recovery Tax Act of 1981, member newsletters, 1981-1982
    - H.R. 4170, 1983-1984
      - Chronological file, 1983-1984, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:168)
      - Senate survey
    - H.R. 4242, 1981
      - Burton amendment
      - Chronological file
      - Task force
    - Internal Revenue Service regulations, 1969
    - Minimum tax, 1985
    - News clippings
      - 1983-1986
      - 1992
    - Preferences of Democratic members to direct Ways and Means committee, survey, 1985
    - Printed matter, 1969, 1985-1986
    - Survey research (Box II:169)
      - 1983
      - 1985
        - Deficit reduction options
        - “National Survey of Attitudes concerning Tax Reform”
          - Report and comments
          - Tabulation
        - “Special Tax Reform Survey”
          - Correspondence
          - House constituents questionnaire, (2 folders)
          - Press conference
          - Tabulation (Box II:170)
            - General, (4 folders)
            - Question 1
            - Question 6, (1 folder) (Box II:171)
            - Question 30 (rate reduction)
            - Summary sheets
      - 1986, 1984-1986
    - Tax fairness letter, 1991
    - Tuition tax credits, 1978
  - Television
    - General, 1966, 1986
    - Smothers Brothers Comedy Hour, 1969
  - Transportation
    - Miscellany, 1968-1970, 1992
    - Safety defects, 1966-1969, (3 folders) (Box II:172)
  - Veto overrides, 1975, (2 folders)
  - Vietnam War
    - Chronological file, 1965-1973, (3 folders)
    - Indochina Resolution, 1973
    - News clippings, 1967-1972
    - “O'Neill Resolution,” 1972
  - Voting (Box II:173)
    - Analyses
      - 90th Congress, 1968
      - 94th Congress, 1975
      - 97th Congress, 1981-1982
      - 98th Congress, 1984-1985
      - 99th Congress, 1985
    - Chairmen, undated
    - Committee votes by congress
      - 92nd Congress, 1971-1972
      - 93rd Congress, 1973-1974
      - 94th Congress, 1975-1976, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:174)
      - 95th Congress, 1977
    - Electronic voting, 1958-1965
    - Presidential elections, role of House, 1967-1969
    - Ratings
      - Analytical explanation, 1983-1985
      - By organizations
        - 1966-1982, (2 folders)
        - 1983-1985 (Box II:175)
    - Southern state representatives, 1968-1970
    - Studies
      - Miscellaneous, 1966-1980, undated, (8 folders)
      - Study, impact of whip system on votes See Containers II:101-102, same heading
  - Voting Rights Act, 1965-1969, (3 folders) (Box II:176)
  - Waggonner, Joseph David, anti-busing legislation 1971-1972, (2 folders)
  - War Powers Resolution
    - Dellums v. Bush, 1990
    - Lowry v. Reagan
      - Background information
        - 1973-1988, (5 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder) (Box II:177)
      - Case file, 1987-1988, (7 folders); (4 folders) (Box II:178)
      - Requests for documents, 1987-1988
  - Watergate scandal, news clippings
    - Index
    - Chronological file
      - 1972
      - 1973
        - Jan. 1-Apr. 18
        - Apr. 19-May 7, (4 folders) (Box II:179)
        - May 8-24, (5 folders) (Box II:180)
        - May 25-June 6, (4 folders) (Box II:181)
        - June 7-30, (4 folders) (Box II:182)
        - July 1-Aug. 20, (4 folders) (Box II:183)
        - Aug. 22-Sept. 2 (Box II:184)
  - Welfare, 1960, 1966-1971
  - White House (Jimmy Carter Administration), survey of performance, 1979
    - Members of Congress
      - Democrats
      - Miscellaneous
      - Republicans
      - Unknown party affiliation (“Blank”)
    - Press and others
    - Staff
      - Democrats
      - Miscellaneous
      - Republicans
      - Unknown party affiliation (“Blank”)
    - Tabulations
  - White House staff authorization bill, 1978
  - Wisconsin state politics, 1972-1973 (Box II:185)
  - Wise, Robert, 1991-1992
  - “Women's View of Washington,” undated
  - Wright, Jim, ethics inquiry, 1988-1989, (2 folders)
- Part II: Formerly Restricted, 1954-1995 (Box II: R186)
  Correspondence and memoranda, meeting records, reports, and printed matter.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Administrative File (Box II:R186)
    - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Container II:3)
    - Executive committee
      - Meetings, 1991-1995 (Container II:9)
    - Legislative service organizations
      - Financing
        - Democratic Study Group, 1994-1995 (Container II:22), (2 folders)
  - Subject File
    - Miscellany
      - Printed matter, 1986-1995, undated (Container II:152)
- Part III: DSG Legislative Report, 1967-1994 (Box III:1-III:11)
  Issues of DSG Legislative Report, a weekly summary of bills and amendments scheduled for action that week.
  Arranged chronologically by year and thereunder by month.
  - 1967-1969, (5 folders) (Box III:1)
  - 1970, Jan.-Aug. See also Container I:5, DSG Legislative Report, (2 folders)
  - 1973, Feb.-Apr.
  - 1976, (8 folders) (Box III:2)
  - 1977
    - Jan.-May, (2 folders)
    - June-Dec., (5 folders) (Box III:3)
  - 1978
    - Jan.-May, (4 folders)
    - June-Oct., (5 folders) (Box III:4)
  - 1981
    - Jan.-July, (3 folders)
    - Aug-Nov., (3 folders) (Box III:5)
  - 1985
    - Jan.-Sept., (6 folders)
    - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box III:6)
  - 1987
    - Jan.-Sept., (5 folders)
    - Oct.-Dec., (3 folders) (Box III:7)
  - 1988
    - Feb.-July, (5 folders)
    - Aug.-Oct., (3 folders) (Box III:8)
  - 1989
    - Feb.-July, (3 folders)
    - Aug.-Nov., (4 folders) (Box III:9)
  - 1990
    - Jan.-July, (4 folders)
    - Sept.-Oct., (3 folders) (Box III:10)
  - 1991
    - Jan.-July, (4 folders)
    - Sept.-Nov., (4 folders) (Box III:11)
  - 1994
    - Jan.-May, (3 folders)
    - June-Nov., (6 folders) (Box III:12)
- Part III: Campaign Memoranda, 1964-1968 (Box III:13)
  Compilations of voting record analyses and other opposition research for use in congressional and national election campaigns.
  Arranged chronologically
  - 1964, 1966-1968, (4 folders) (Box III:13)
- Part III: Daily Report, 1990-1993 (Box III:13-III:14)
  Daily notification of bills and amendments scheduled for action that day.
  - 1990, (4 folders) (Box III:13)
  - 1991
    - Jan.-Aug., (2 folders)
    - Sept.-Oct. (Box III:14)
  - 1992-1993, (6 folders)
- Part III: Fact Sheet, 1976-1991 (Box III:14-III:16)
  Publication analyzing major legislation.
  - 1976, (2 folders) (Box III:14)
  - 1990, (8 folders) (Box III:15)
  - 1991
    - Jan.-May
    - June-Dec., (4 folders) (Box III:16)
- Part III: Research Publications, 1964-1969 (Box III:16-III:17)
  Bibliography compilation and Research Memoranda.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or title.
  - Research bibliography compilation, 1960-1992 (Box III:16)
  - Research Memoranda
    - 1964-1966, (3 folders)
    - 1967-1969, (3 folders) (Box III:17)
- Part III: Miscellany, 1969-1997 (Box III:17)
  Histories of the Democratic Study Group, Issue Report issues, agency contact and interest group lists, and a tax reform booklet.
  Arranged alphabetically by title or type of material.
  - Agency contact list, 1989, 1998 (Box III:17)
  - Histories of the Democratic Study Group, 1993
  - Interest group lists, 1997
  - Issue Report, 1990
  - Tax Reform, a DSG Fact Book, 1969